[Music]
welcome to the second edition of the
Outlook money insurance Summit the topic
of discussion is the rise of bite-sized
insurance and the utility and we have
with us eminent industry leaders Anand
Roy managing director at Star health and
Allied Insurance parav Das Gupta
managing director and CEO at icsa
Lombard General insurance and tapen
singel managing director and CEO Bajaj
Alliance General Insurance a very Happy
New Year to all of you and thank you so
much for joining me for this
discussion so bite-sized insurance is
something that is very uh new for the
insurance industry and with the Advent
of digitization it has got a major leg
up in the last uh two years and it has
opened up interesting Avenues of
providing a cover across the landscape
of General insurance but it also leads
to the fear that you know somewhere in
this rush to buy low ticket immediate
use kind of policies the focus will go
away from the importance of
comprehensive covers but starting the
discussion about these policies that are
really The Talk of the Town in the
insurance sector right now um I'll uh
you know throw the first question to all
of you is what do you think is behind
the rise of this kind of insurance maybe
Parov you could start with that yeah
thanks nii and thank you for having us
here um you know while there is a lot
more talk about bze insurance now as you
rightly identified uh there is lot more
awareness and maybe even advertisement
but actually byze insurance policies
have been there at a smaller scale I
remember back in 2006 or 7 we had
launched a 50 rupe you know outpatient
uh policy for the rural markets part of
our social Outreach Initiative Program
uh of course it hadn't kind of scaled
into the you know the uh Urban markets
at that point in time and I think the
point that you're making about you this
becoming quite uh popular now is as I
said because of maybe the Advent of two
or three things one the digital
distribution which makes it easy to uh I
relatively easy at lower cost to sell
these products second is I would say a
large number of fintech players you know
payment companies you know
aggregators uh you know bnpl companies
uh who are looking to attach uh you know
contextual policies to their customers
to increase you know the the
relationship depth with their customers
so that I would say would be the second
major reason apart from the digitization
uh but the need was always there and I
think it's just that some of these
changes that has happened in the
ecosystem is helping us uh do more with
this kind of uh these kind of products
in the market okay and then then T would
you like to add something to this what
is leading to this kind of Rise uh of
bik sized Insurance according to
you an you going first after you sure I
just uh I will just you know concur with
what bav mentioned you know the concept
is not new uh I remember also way back
uh we started off with travel insurance
was also a type of a bite-sized product
you know where people could buy
insurance for exactly the number of days
they would travel as compared to what
used to be earlier a package policy
where which was you know predefined so I
think you know bite size concept has
always been there but uh now with the
onset of you know lot of online
e-commerce and uh stuff I think there is
a opportunity to cross sell and attach
relevant Insurance uh coverages along
with the products that customers are
buying online so I think you know it has
become more popular now of course but
yes uh the bite-sized product concept
has always been prevalent in the
insurance industry not so largely as it
is right now okay tap like Anan
mentioned I think it's also to do with
the Advent of e-commerce companies like
uh you know these your Olas and Ubers
with which you are seeing these policies
attached to really think those are also
a nudge towards these so first
understand this that are people buying B
insurance or is it bundle know before we
get into that is it really know taking
off or is it the new thing or The New
Normal happening see one of the dilemmas
for the insurance industry has been
across ages that know people don't get
up to buy insurance
so I think most of the insurance that
let if I talk about General Insurance
know being sold is what is mandatory
either by Bankers or by law or which is
requirement know and health obviously
has picked up pretty good now which is
not mandatory but people feel the need
of it and and they see the high H cost
happening so that's picking up so bite
size to me has been very interesting lot
of it is bundled I think the customer
just gets it if you ask 10 customers
that do you have you do you know that
you got an insurance with no this right
of yours I surprised to see if no nine
of them say yes yes I'm aware I I
consciously took it from but there are
some bites insurance which actually has
taken off let's say the mobile Insurance
again a need like I mentioned health
insurance took off because people
realize the need of it and and they felt
that they should have a good health
cover because it makes a difference know
when you see this huge hospitalization
cost happening mobile Insurance again
I've seen that people see the need of it
because mobiles do break and they find
that no they're able to other too
expensive and a lot of people buy fancy
mobiles and very expensive ones and they
see that going on so there I've seen
people consciously buy but in like most
insurance products I've seen byze also
most of it still goes as bundle some of
it conscious pickup has happened now
leaving that aside it's a new
distribution which has come through
because the ease and you can sell the
small ticket size without the cost of
selling it let's say in earlier times
like bav mentioned or Anand mentioned
that bite size is not new there were
enough policies no I think not even in
2000 I remember early '90s also 1986
also you had all this PA policies and
all and even today a personal accident
policy for one lakh cover no death only
cost you 40 rupees a year is it not
bized and such a amazing kind of product
then what else will it be bized but to
sell a 40 rupees policy with the
distribution which was not digital that
time no uh it would not happen because
of the distribution cost required so
with the Advent of e-commerce with the
Advent of dation with this obviously
small ticket size products can be sold
now and they are viable because you
don't have to spend so much on
Distribution on that basis so it's a
it's a phenomena which is going to stay
is going to get powerful over time you
think but it is also evolving like other
lines of businesses and that is my view
on
this but uh also I would like uh to ask
you gentlemen but uh what what about you
are saying that distribution is become
perhaps easier because they're they're
coming bundled with other services but
uh what about uh I mean uh you know I
take a byes Insurance perhaps for a trip
to the airport and I I don't face any
challenge the next time because you know
so many times it happens that you know
you uh book a ticket and you don't take
travel insurance a lot of times most of
us you know don't click on that uh uh
option of taking travel insurance
especially it's if it's a domestic but H
do you think that this can be
sustainable in the long run as people
will get used to it because this whole
thing of renewal distribution is there
is no direct phase that is you know
making you understand that you might
need it or you may not need it it is up
to you your decision whether you are
going to take it up or not so do you
think it can uh you know translate into
a habit you want to go first reverse the
order thank you V yeah so I think what
excites us is that for us the biggest
challenge is not about products I think
insurance industry has amazing products
honestly I've been all of the product
the industry has not because I'm part of
the industry but it's amazing for the
price they offer the challenge has been
the need and awareness of it know
because these are um low frequency and
high impact event and people don't think
it'll happen to them no that is a
challenge for industry so the way we
look at it is the more uh people get
used to having insurance and they may or
may not have exhausted it or taken a
claim out of it which is not the purpose
behind no that everybody has to take a
claim only then they should start
accepting it but the more they see
things happening around them know let's
say when you saw Co happen people really
bought covid policies no I think start
shooting you will see things happening
around them and they know that these are
the means through which they can get an
insurance know on the fight know really
wherever they're going let's say travel
insurance lot of people Dlisted which is
actually interesting if you look at the
cost of the travel insurance on on any
website is about 100 rupees plus huh
you're paying a ticket for 8,000 rupees
but for the 100 rupees we will either
know take out The Tick box and not do it
but fundamentally we think about it if
you pay 100 rupes more also ready to pay
for like say 250 rupees for a cup of tea
in a in a flight some tell people
jokingly that we should carry our own
tea bags with us ask for hot water and
you have it no instead of paying 250
rupees for a cup of tea there but for
100 rupees insurance we will know D take
it so I think the way I look at it the
more such kind of initiatives happen the
more customers are aware about it they
may or may not feel the need of it but
as awareness level goes up as people see
it and they need more about it these
things will pick up so it has its own
Journey n so I don't think that know
there's something that we should worry
about renewals not happening I don't
think that we should worry about know
people decking we should make this
continuous effort of creating awareness
we should make this continuous effort of
offering amazing products to the
customers of high value to them and then
no I think as time progresses these
things pick up so that's my view on that
okay so and what do you think is is it
really a utility based uh you know are
these really utility based products and
people will take up take it up like you
know tap is saying that eventually the
uptake will increase as awareness
increases Etc absolutely I totally agree
because see um people are realizing that
you know people are buying more
expensive stuff uh people are buy taking
more trips and bsize insurance is as
both bav and tap mentioned it's a
contextual in nature you know when
you're you are actually purchasing
something and you feel the need to
protect that uh purchase that you're
making and here is an offering which is
very very reasonably priced and you
don't you don't mind you know uh adding
that on as an add-on so I think that's
the context but uh you know from a uh I
come from a pure play health insurance
background so from a health insurance
point of view you know bite size is not
something which is very very relevant
because I believe you know at a health
insurance concept or even for that
matter for a life insurance you know and
the protection plans should be
comprehensive in nature because see at
the end of the day you want to give
something which the customer will
actually get derive the true benefit out
of it okay there's no point in selling
something for a very short period or of
a for a context and when there is a need
for the insurance it doesn't serve its
purpose I'm talking about health and you
know in general so I think you know bite
size uh in health insurance is not very
very uh relevant as far as I'm concerned
but what is more relevant is how can we
make the premium bite-sized okay to the
customer so that you know they look at
the product as a bite-sized product so
can we offer them an install premium
payments and installments can we bring
all this new technology like bnpl and
all of that on the health platform so
that eventually it becomes a bite-sized
purchase for the customer but all the
same time getting a comprehensive
coverage I think that's how I look at it
from a health insurance point of view uh
so yeah please go go ahe no I was saying
you know just to uh you know complete
the thought process picking up on what
tapan said I think one of the beauty of
General Insurance is that uh we can
conceptually cover every type of risk
that a consumer uh you know perceives
and as life business Society becomes
more complex new type of risks emerge
and really it's an opportunity for us as
an industry to create uh products which
uh address those risks in a manner that
consumers find Value which is the point
that you know tap was making and if you
look at uh you know adding to that point
if you look at one of the I think the
cultural mindset of uh India has been
traditionally India has been
traditionally a uh Society where family
comes in to support you right and as you
become more urban more nuclear uh I
think people begin to realize that you
need to fend for yourself as well I mean
you can of course you all OB all of us
depend on family for many things but you
do need to defend for yourself and as
Society progresses uh people think of
protecting themselves for from some of
these uh you know new age risks uh just
to talk talk about couple of new things
for example you know let's say cyber T
talked about mobile very very relevant I
mean 10 years back that wasn't a
relevant category of product in a sense
right because there was no need to buy
you know there was no mobile mobile
phones in that sense Smartphones at that
time and you didn't need to protect it
today if you look at it cyber Insurance
um you know the exposure and the risk
wasn't there 10 years back uh today it
is there and you need to protect
yourself so I think it's really a you
know beautiful industry in a sense that
we can actually geter to very very new
emerging types of risks and we have to
do it in a manner that uh is contextual
it's easy to understand maybe initially
a bit you know inexpensive so so that
people start exploring and using them
and as that as people do that you know
the spreads and you know people end up
buying more and more products as Society
changes okay so another thought that
comes to my mind uh regarding white size
is that you know when it comes to uh the
rural and semiurban areas or uh you
could call it Tire three Tire four or
even Tire two cities I mean especially
the low income groups the small ticket
size is something that may attract them
even in health health insurance even in
other General Insurance categories but
the other challenge is that you know a
lot of these uh you know policies are
also since they bundled with say
e-commerce platforms and others there's
an element of digitization attached to
them uh to a large extent so uh you know
but the there may be digitization
challenges in these areas that the
categories that I was mentioning so how
does that Gap kind of how does that come
together in terms of uh servicing of
insurance or servicing of these kind of
products to these kind of segments so uh
anyone could could take this question
please I think we reverse the order
again
bar let's follow that as a n yeah okay
sure so yeah ni I think that's a great
point and you know as I started all of
us have had products and you know we had
done some experimentation in the rural
Market exactly the point that you're
making and Rural Market is a segment
where you have to make it more
affordable I mean you know the entire
Market is potentially just a bite-sized
Market
but it is in my mind a fallacy that
digitization and digital payments is not
prevalent in the rural markets at least
our experience is today almost 50 to 60%
of payments that we are seeing from the
rural markets is uh is digital payments
uh there are other uh um you know
distribution models that are emerging uh
you know riding on existing uh you know
models for example the government CSC
platform right so the CSC platform is a
very interesting uh outreach program to
from the insurance perspective to use a
existing platform to again provide very
lowcost insurance policies these could
be standard you know Motor Vehicles or
tractor or you know you know small
ticket personal accident or small ticket
Health policies uh most of the processes
are completely digitize just to ensure
the cost is minimized otherwise you
can't afford to do it so actually it's
happening what you have to do is uh
again think of the customer at the end
of the day design the product that is
easy to understand consume and claim uh
so that the experience is positive and
you build a positive Awareness on the
ground so my experience is that you know
even for the rural Market digital you
know the biz insurance is becoming very
very popular not the same type of B
insurance that is prevalent in the urban
markets but products that are relevant
for the rural markets yeah just to add
to that I think uh totally agree uh
because see uh the key is the relevance
okay keeping the customer at the end of
the you know that's keeping them at the
center of the entire offering because uh
rural does not mean the aspirations are
lower okay the rural markets have very
high aspirations they are looking
forward to getting the best uh you know
treatments or best facilities or best
Services uh what other large cities are
getting so I think you know the bite
size is totally contextual uh and it is
not Market relevant it is more you know
on the uh on the purchase Journey the
customer is looking forward to and in
that context I think what we have to do
today is you know uh to increase the
penetration of health insurance I think
bite-sized products are a great
beginning you know because at at least
at the younger age group we see that
people look at these products more from
you know understanding what insurance
can actually cover because insurance as
both the panelists mentioned here can
cover almost everything today in India
and I think that's a very very good uh
entry into the world of insurance for
the Young younger age segment uh
especially people who are you know using
these platforms on the e-commerce sites
and all of that and probably try to
cross sell more comprehensive products
to them as we go along so that you know
they become more protected in the true
sense of the you know the word and I
think that's the way we have to look at
this uh b-size products okay T you want
to weigh in on this yeah N I think first
and foremost to and VAV did allude to
that that to say that disly Sav is not
there in the rural side or no in the
stata which is no as we
call upcoming is wrong because I think
if you just check with know at least my
domestic help is on Facebook my V vendor
is on Facebook and you look at rural
India also I think we do a lot of
business there um most people are on
Facebook and uh and if I look at the
sale of Amazon flip cart is more in in
know the T tier three than in tier one
no if I look at the bigger Brands being
sold it's more in the smaller towns so I
think India has changed a lot from what
we think and what we know still have a
view on so obviously like Anand also
mentioned that know the aspirations are
there now it's up to the industry how do
we cater to that which is relevant know
and contextual from that perspective
more than getting to products how do we
service the claims I think that is what
is very very critical know the
infrastructure to service the claims is
what the industry and the industry is
doing a job barav did mention about CSC
I think CSC is an amazing infrast setup
and the government collaboration of the
amount of government businesses
happening be it crop insurance be the
government Health business reach is
there and the servicing is happening and
people are experiencing um claims now
infr is getting created so for me
personally I feel that if five years
from now we have a panel like this and
all of us are here again this question
would not have relevance because the
market would actually have become very
very interesting very big and very very
you know powerful its own way because
the creation is happening like I was
mentioning to you and people have wealth
it is not they don't have wealth and
like people like Anand have set a strong
infrastructure for health in the smaller
towns and cities no the buildup is
happening n so we just have to wait and
watch and I I think the industry is
working on it and we shall see more of
it happening and bite size will also
happen in the places but right now it's
mostly government driven and you have
this smaller two wheeler V and all which
is happening but why not for a
agriculture pump set a Bice side
Insurance know why not for a small like
three month or two month crops know
small like strawberry crop know why
should not be which is the V of nature
why should be know small B so potential
is there and I'm very hopeful very know
sure that this is actually going to take
up pretty well okay so uh one thing that
you mentioned uh Mr single was uh claims
so what what what is the claims uh you
know scenario as of now because I
understand that you know this Market is
not very huge as of now it's still in
its initial stages though it has started
uh ahead for the past couple of years
but uh what about the claim settlement
is there any uh you know is there
satisfaction at that level because these
are small and these are you know a lot
of lot of times maybe you know I take a
take a bite-size insurance but uh maybe
because the you know amount is small
maybe I you need it exactly at that time
how how much how many customers are
actually coming back to make those
claims and how much of it is really
getting settled
also yeah N I think first and all let me
talk about the industry a small hurt of
the industry and then I'll come to the
specific question that you have if you
look at the hurt of the industry the
industry is combined ratio for now 16
years I'm not wrong correct me wrong
it's been close to 115 to 120% to give
you just a rough idea of combine ratio
it means for every 100 rupes industry
Tak 120 is the outgo no and for even
amazing big e-commerce companies which
we hear are so customer Centric they
lose five to six to every 100 know here
the industry losing 15 20 that mean
they're paying claims through the nose
still people have lot of view on the
industry that know they don't pay claim
so I thought just park this point here
the industry plays games very very well
and it PS it very uh very gracefully
also so out of 100 customers no the
claim settlement figures was really uh
you know good this time the I report
that came in December always so I think
it's been The Whipping Boy of everybody
of the media houses of of the ministers
so I think it's a bit unfortunate I'll
take this forum you know T if I may
weigh and support the point that t is
making because he'll move on to some
other point you know we had studied not
just we AS Global consultant had studied
all the financial services sectors the
number of let's say bank account or
policies or you know customer you know
customers Etc and the number of
complaints GI industry had the lowest
percentage but even though the claim
number that we pay is very very large
back to you just to support the point
think a very very good point so the
point I should make is B the industry PS
amazing claims
99.999% customers would be very happy
with it no the point that the gance
ratio is know it runs into like less
than a percent is 0 Z something no I
forgot the exact number they're very
happy the ones who are dissatisfied
because the industry is already vipping
boy and that big noise that no this not
good now let's come to the bite-sized
one we have been one of the largest
mobile insurer no I think we started
very early on and we can settle claims
remotely so it does not matter that no
the mobile if damage has to come to our
office or somebody has to go for a
survey there which damage remotely we
assess the claim and transfer the money
to account you know so claims do happen
mobile claims do happen loss St in a
mobile insurance is pretty pretty high
it is not that no uh the L and we all
know n genuinely so many of our mobiles
do get broken you try your best to save
it with the life know and so many jokes
there somebody fell down with a new
iPhone then the question not that did
your bone crack or no is the phone safe
people I think that is the kind of
protection people but still it does
happen so claims do happen May in B
Insurance it does happen and I think as
I said some categories in which it
happens more frequently some does not
happen like a ride insurance would be
very low frequency but very high
severity but something like mobile
insurance it's is very high frequency
and know and it does happen and the
assessment happens remotely and the
money gets transferred you'll be
surprised to know that the transform
money can happen within the 30 minutes
of the mobile getting broken even if you
are in the farthest part of the country
where there's no access but at least you
can access the internet if you if you
can reach internet and you're in in a
place like that like sitting on top of
mountain internet connection is there
your claim will get settled no so I
think most companies have buil up this
competence so claim settlement is
something obviously that is our main
bread and butter if we don't SLE claims
well how can we know be in the industry
so I think we we do that yeah so no so
the idea was more to ask whether you
know people are actually coming for
claims rather than settlement it happens
they do yes yeah so Anand I wanted to
ask you in terms of health insurance so
when you talk about you know breaking
health insurance into bite-sized
products later uh what you talked about
earlier about this concept of uh how
bite size can be you know you brought
into health insurance how would you uh
you know there is when it comes to
health insurance there is a list of
exclusions and you know medical uh you
know uh medical tests and all that
people have to uh go through to you know
to be eligible for a certain claim or a
certain policy or a certain product how
would you kind of uh you know marry the
two together yeah so uh in the context
of health insurance see as I told you
I'm of the strong believer that the cage
should be comprehensive the premiums can
be bite-sized can be made bite-sized
okay and that's I think that's the
combination that will stick uh with our
you know potential customers but uh
let's talk about uh the current you know
scenario in health insurance and some of
the products that were introduced which
will fall technically let's say in the
bite-size segment you know there are
products which cover specific diseases
you know for example denu or chicken Gia
or for that matter you know uh the
products which covers
OPD you know treatments alone and of
recently in the current context of the
pandemic you know the industry did
launch a product for the covering only
Corona specific you know treatment and I
think that was really uh something which
was in time in the midst of a pandemic
the entire industry came together to
offer a product to you know to protect
the society at large which was very you
know uh what do you say vulnerable and I
think you know these are the kind of
things that the insurance industry and
The General insurance industry in
particular has done but as far as health
insurance is concerned you know uh I
strongly believe that you know uh
customers should look for a
comprehensive coverage and uh we will be
able to make that coverage more uh
palatable by making the premium bite
size I think that's that's what I would
like to stick my argument on uh because
I do not believe frankly that uh short
period cover or a disease specific cover
for 2 months 3 months is a proper uh
protection being offered and at the end
of the day insurance is a you know
subject of protection so we do not want
to offer something that would be uh not
uh available at the time of need you
know and I think that's what I would
like to insist upon so Anand has been
continuously raising this uh issue of uh
you know comprehensive insurance and
that is uh you know one of my thoughts
also that uh
do you think that Biz bit-sized
Insurance in any way can kind of dilute
this Market or the need for
comprehensive insurance especially when
it comes to uh Health even personal
accident for that matter because that is
also uh you know which is a large cover
in the biz space uh what are your views
on that so let's look at different
categories I think what Anand is saying
is very relevant in the health uh
segment uh which is you know the segment
that he's is talking about uh and if you
look at the general insurance multi-line
General insurance companies we provide
Health as also other categories of
product and going back to the point that
I made that there are different types of
emerging risks that are that are there
and uh every single type of risk need
not require a product which is very
expensive you can actually design
products which are relatively cheap you
know and bite size and relevant for the
context of the customers risk and let me
give you a small example I mean you know
in the same you talk about personal
accident personal accident any anyway is
a Biz product because the size is very
very low but true but if you think about
even a PA policy uh when I'm traveling
in a in a in a certain terrain I want a
policy for let's say 15 days because
that's the period that I think I'm at
risk why shouldn't I you know get a
product like that I I don't see any
issue with developing and providing such
products to customers because it's it's
relevant and contextual for the customer
we have to think put ourselves in the
shoes of the customer and think about
what is it that is relevant for the
customer and design those products un
point is absolutely valid when you think
about your health you need to buy
something competence but the types of
risks that we cover in in multi-line
general insurance companies is mult
multifarious it's not just for health
it's across different categories you
know cyber Insurance you may buy a
policy which is even as low as 50 lakhs
sorry 50 rupees and you get a production
of 50,000 Rupees you know as a as a
consumer I'm happy with the production
of 50,000 Rupees that's good enough for
me if I want to buy a cover which gives
me even higher production that's fine
coming back to even Health uh I
personally believe what Biz insurance
does is make people conscious and aware
there is an affordability issue across
different startups of society and when
you're first coming into the into that
insurance consumption bracket as a
consumer you may want to experiment with
you know smaller products and then you
realize that this is not going to cover
you for everything that's a in a sense a
good entry point to buy the
comprehensive products that Anand
rightly talks about so I think the mood
point that I'm making is uh you know
horses for courses different types of
risk that customers have different needs
that customers have we as an industry
have to design products and give them in
a manner that is easy to understand
consume and
clean that's what our job is so is it
also like uh something like what you
suggesting perhaps is like creating uh
uh a menu which is a testing menu so
that you know uh consumers can take on
uh go on with the full menu later to
understand the comprehensive to
understand Insurance the basics of
insurance what it can do to you how it
can protect you and then go on for a
comprehensive cover because even when it
comes to these kind of trip insurance
and you know these small kind of
insurance policies there is always uh
this argument also that you could take a
comprehensive travel insurance if you
are a uh you know frequent flyer though
you
know absolutely you're right I mean you
can take a comprehensive cover and we
see people who buy covers for a longer
period and pay a bit more premium on
travel in specifically because they
travel a few times in a year and it
makes sense for them to buy a maybe a
long-term uh cover U so your point is
absolutely making the same point that
I'm making that you know I think it
expands the P it you know opens up the
market for uh for multiple you know
segments of customers uh young
Millennials who may otherwise wait till
the age of 35 to buy health insurance
May experiment with some small ticket
covers and uh and that builds awareness
that builds connect with with the
insurance provider uh and opens up the
market uh you know is my belief and
that's a positive so but what has been
the experience so far K uh maybe you
could take that uh is is it really
working like that that you know people
are coming for these small insurance
policies and understanding it and taking
it Forward uh to say a comprehensive
policy or a you know a policy that gives
them wider
coverage it's I think any answer to
those should be too early to give no uh
so I cannot say that we have seen a
clear pattern about it the point that
bav mentioned the way you said the
tasting meno no before the I think it's
a very powerful Point see somebody and
most people don't buy insurance dollar
the insurance is not only under
insurance but under penetrated and we
all know about it no people don't buy it
at all now let's say if they get used to
buying it and they start looking at it
then they obviously would think why not
this no and they can afford it somebody
going on a 15-day trip know they must be
spending at least 30 4,000 rupees so
they can pretty well afford something
which is 45 rupees know so the let's
understand the difference bze insurance
and full-blown cover I think that also
interesting point we underestimate this
a bze ins talking about 10 20 rupees a
fullblown insurance May cost 500 700
rupees no a travel insurance policy or
let's say what an talking about Al
full-blown Health cover will cost ,500
rupees so the the beauty is that we
talking of huge difference somebody
spending about 50 60,000 on a trip can
afford a 2,500 full cover also know if
somebody's ready to pay 50 70 rupees for
Bice insurance now let me give a
personal example today I may say that
I'm over insured no but I love to be
over insured know once I understand the
insurance products any insurance you
think about you know I think the we were
the first to launch retail cyber
Insurance my daughters bought the first
two policies in India know every policy
you think of I'd be having it for myself
the moment you understand the beauty of
insurance I promise you you'll buy all
this policy we can afford it they
expensive policies when you talk a
full-blown it's not like you're going to
buy a very expensive product you're
talking a couple of thousand rupees
that's all as a full-blown cover and buy
a toet of couple of know like 100 or no
50 70 rupees so once people start
getting used to looking at insurance I
have a personal belief that they will go
in for the full-blown cover but do do we
have a pattern to give you you the right
answer right now the answer is no I
think it is still emerging as the
pattern emerges it should happen but
that is my belief n so another thing
that I wanted to ask you that you
know like you were saying you know
understanding of insurance is very
important but we do see that you know a
lot of people still do not understand a
lot of insurance policies let alone life
and health which are like the basic even
The General Insurance even motor for
that uh matter which is you know quite
uh it's it's one of the most popular
ones because you know everybody has to
buy motor before they can drive out the
cars out of the showrooms so when it
comes to Biz insurance I know the ticket
size is very low so I I might be low but
uh you know in terms of these insurance
policies also do come with their own
terms and conditions it they might be
smaller in on you know on scale and
compared to other policies and all so
how do you think that awareness that Gap
can be filled
anyone of you can take this question you
absolutely right uh I think enough has
been said on the fact that customers
don't understand and you know I think we
make a lot of effort you know I know you
know T makes we make in terms of trying
to make it as easy and you know simple
for the customer to understand but it's
a it's a it's a it's a task I think one
of the advantages of some of these
bite-sized products is uh that they are
actually even more simpler than some of
the comprehensive products and when
they're simpler the the benefits are
very very uh if I can call it almost
binary you know event of this nature
happens you get a certain lumpsum
payment uh if you look at Insurance
there are two types of insurance
fundamentally two types of insurance one
is indemnification so your whatever is
your extent of loss we will reimburse
that and the second is benefit you know
whatever may be a loss I will pay you a
fixed amount the advantage of the buyze
insurance is most of them are largely
benefit constu as in you pay get a fixed
amount of money in the event something
uh you know unfortunate happens right so
let's say a vector Bond disease you know
you have a Deni cover of 50,000 Rupees
you get Deni we will pay you 50,000 you
have a mobile Insurance the mobile you
know breaks I will give you you know
let's say 25,000 so it's easier to
communicate and the other thing that has
happened is on a digital platform you
can actually break down the features and
the benefits in a very simple manner so
that it's easy for customers to uh
understand and and I think that is one
of the strengths of some of these bites
is product constructs that we see in the
market I think bab put it very
beautifully the bites is actually much
simpler than the comprehensive one now
having said that nidi let me give you a
very simple principle I think it also
surprises me when people talk of
complication of GI products why it
surprises me is that if if we are aware
of just one thing anything which is
damaged or know has pre-existing or
where the loss is already you know
happened or is happening does not get
covered I think know if if this
principally we we understand this then
whatever you buying for actually know
would be covered subject to some
depreciation let me put no very simple
principle now when you put this two
sentences and apply it anywhere you'll
find that most of what you bought is
actually covered for the dispute starts
happening for is when you go for these
kind of segments in which no you start
feeling that no the pre exting should
have been covered or my previous damage
should have been covered or I paid the
premium of five years why should I get
my previous damages happening I think
that is what dispute happen dispute
never happens on the product never
happens understanding I think so I think
this also has been which I say a hurt of
the industry lot of people say it's
complex and I ask them okay what's
complex in a motor car what's complex
your car meets an accident no whatever
in the accident has happened will get
paid now you have scratches in the car
that's not an accident that's
maintenance no so what's the complex
part of it insurance companies will
cover accident yeah and anything in
accident will get Faith it's as simple
as that Health if you have something of
an illness already there with you now no
company no typically would cover that so
it would just mean that when you bought
a policy and anything develops later
than that gets paid immediately you know
so I think it is not very complex
against a mindset issue which I strongly
believe and when B mentioned benefit
policies it's so amazing you know you
buy a policy let's say dingo or you buy
for catract and if it happens you get
the full amount paid no question asked
where can you get such simple products
ni I think again this industry as I
always say sometime get surprised this
talk of complication ask people tell me
what's complicated in this no I think
just the two sent I mentioned to you
just keep that as a principle for any
insurance and the name the product and
then see what is not paid it's all paid
it's as as simple as that but bite size
is actually more simpler more easy and
it more straight through I think because
that's why b s will work as it not work
I think that's perhaps why uh what is
adding to its popularity also the
Simplicity uh in nature and also the
utility because of which we are
discussing this topic also so do you
guys think that you know this this kind
of insurance is for everyone or do you
really think that it's only for a
particular segment uh maybe the younger
generation who doesn't want to look at
compr who's not ready to look at
comprehensive covers yet maybe they
should but maybe they're not ready or
you know that segment which is uh just
ready for the those low ticket size
insurance policies
uh par could you take that yeah so I I
don't personally believe that it's
designed for a certain segment but it's
obviously the younger po you know the
Millennials the younger people who are
actually uh more digitally Savvy you
know using Ola for example when you when
you have a ride healing service uh
anyone who uses Ola or Uber is buying
you know some of these you know one rupe
policies Etc that you that you that you
talked about so coincident I mean you
know given the nature of the customer
segment that uses the fintech and the
digital and e-commerce platforms yes you
are see more younger population buying
this but it is not designed necessarily
for just younger people it is actually
designed for anyone who uses those
services and there is risk that they are
bearing because of the use of those
services so tapan do you also think that
you know it's meant for everyone you of
course mentioned that you know your
daughter and you you know you are over
insured and you end up buying all kinds
of policies so it's it it's uh pretty
much out there people like you and me
every everybody should be taking up
these policies when you know taking an
Ola ride or perhaps uh you know ordering
in
food yeah I think when I look at my
family my younger daughter and my father
they are the most digital savy people I
think so I think again these are all I
think when when I listen n now look at
experiences I think the myths and the
reality is very different so I can
guarant my father can beat me to any
kind of e-commerce sites any purchases
any kind of know ride Hing taxes or I
still am lost at it so he is more he
tells me more about B Insurance than I
can know talk about know from what is
happening across or my younger daughter
can interesting so when you look at the
Spectrum I think they both are very
powerful the issue which comes through
is that how are we as an industry able
to put together things of interest for
all Spectrum we should never think that
this spectrum of no customers would not
be available that is a that's a myth I
don't agree I think industry how can we
broader the Spectrum and how can we
cater to every you know section of
customers is what we should be working
on so and the work is already happening
I can see lot of prods at different
spectrums coming through but I think we
should cover the entire thing not think
that only the Millennials now
Millennials also getting old now I think
we we have to talk about the Gen Z Now
gen Z exactly
genzi now so we should actually get it
to all Spectrum but we should not think
that they don't they they all really you
know understand and and look at it very
well so uh you know summing up uh is
bite size here to stay and what other
Innovations do you think are baiting in
the wings yeah of course it is here to
stay and I think it'll keep on
increasing in size and scope and as I
said you know as new uh use cases emerge
new uh you know products you know that
people use emerge new risks emerge new
products will get designed and I think
there is a scope for tremendous
innovation in in our country in terms of
uh addressing very very episodic risks
of individuals and providing them
through bitsize insurance I think you
know as long as the the environment is
uh open in terms of allowing these
Innovations I think there's a tremendous
scope for growth of some of these
products so I think our industry that is
very lucky we cover risks and you see
how risk keeps on evolving so it's a n
ending process so every third day you
have a new risk now we thought when we
started with the Corona virus thought a
couple of months phenomena now it's year
phenomena now we see people think it's
going to stay phenomena so look at any
cyber risk which has come through or
know it's constantly evolving so imagine
which industry can talk of on a monthly
basis you have something new coming up
no if you look at catastrophic losses
now happening not five in a year when we
were kids when it was a rainy day in 3
four years time and school used to get
closed used to get so excited today even
if floods happen School are getting
closed no times have no completely
changed and every third four months is
happening so one the options of creating
something relevant for customers solving
some customers worries or risk is always
there it's a continuous process two the
ease of process and the ease of getting
claims and getting the customer Delight
is always there it's a constant process
you need to keep on with the tech
getting better every day you keep on
pushing yourself and keep on innovating
to deliver on that basis third with this
bite size coming through can you imagine
the pleora of insurance that can be
offered well if you tell me right now to
start listing down bite size that we can
offer between bav me and Anand I promise
you for the next one hour we will not
stop no from the same main products we
create 100 Biz products
no so the point is there's so much to do
and how do we spread the Spectrum how do
customers know uh Rees what we are
offering and see value in it and how
does it expand to the next level is
there so I think for our industry
there's never dull moment beat for
Innovation for things to stay and bite
size is going to stay and it's going to
become more and more popular time
progresses because of tech usage I think
know people will find relevance of a
shter duration products and they'll make
it much more powerful more beautiful my
last question to sum up the session was
that you know what are the innovations
that are waiting in the wings and uh is
B sized here to stay really yeah yeah
absolutely and uh you know I can't
better what
tap and bav has said they put it so
wonderfully because see bite size is a
concept you know it's not something that
is uh you know that is going to go away
at all because it's it's a concept
that's going to evolve now probably it
may not be one rupee 10 Rupees Insurance
it may evolve into something you know
more contextual based on what the
customer demands and customer needs are
and from a health insurance perspective
you know I would say that you know
definitely there are opportunities to uh
Subs segment and categorize the products
and make cheaper offerings so that
affordable offerings so that you know
more and more people can come into the
Ambit of health insurance whether it is
in the semi-urban areas or within the
urban areas itself we can look at you
know various kinds of offerings there
are OPD products and Dental products
which can be offered on the bite-size
platform and uh I think all of us are
working on that so as a concept this is
not going to go away most important is
how can we ensure that the services are
uh the promises that are made on the
bite-sized products are kept up so that
you know the uh the stickiness of Health
I mean the insurance itself will keep on
improving going forward and hopefully
these bite-sized customers in the long
run we will get more data as we go along
will become uh full-time comprehensive
customers of having over insurance as T
mentioned and making sure that they get
all and all comprehensive coverage in
all segments of their you know lives so
that's what we looking forward to thank
you so much gentlemen for throwing light
on this new area I mean a lot of people
they might be around like you guys
mentioned that these uh policies have
been around for long but a lot of
customers may not have known uh you know
before one or two years in the recent
past so thanks a lot for joining me on
this discussion and uh good day to you
guys thank thank you thank you for thank
you thank you thank you bye bye thank
you bye thank you
[Music]